<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Sincerely Sohani - Sohani Rao</title><link href="/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="/feeds/sohani-rao.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>/</id><updated>2021-08-08T18:40:02-07:00</updated><subtitle>A personal blog by Sohani Rao</subtitle><entry><title>The Waiting Game</title><link href="/2019/09/the-waiting-game-essay.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-09-26T10:20:00-07:00</published><updated>2021-08-01T16:15:36-07:00</updated><author><name>Sohani Rao</name></author><id>tag:None,2019-09-26:/2019/09/the-waiting-game-essay.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;About seeing northern lights dance in Alaska...&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;It's dark and cold. It's Sept 2019, 2 am and I am barely awake. I have been sitting on the porch of my cabin, about 20 miles from the city center of Fairbanks. There are no city lights or any lights, except the soft red light from my lamp. My Aurora app tells me the light show is happening right now above Fairbanks, AK but I cannot see it. I have a clear view of the open sky that has had a thick cover of clouds. As I set down my cup of hot chocolate and breathe out visibly into the cold air, I notice my desperation. After all that I have screwed up this year and all that I had to let go of, I need a win, I need to see the aurora. That need for a good memory for the year had prompted me to book a flight last minute and make a trip out here. And now here I am, playing the waiting game. Yet again. Why is everything worth having packaged into a catch-22? The Aurora Borealis is only visible in the winter and that's when its often so cloudy that you can't see it.&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Eventually, I give up. I grab my purse, throw in some red bulls in there along with some gloves, and my GPS. I lock up the cabin and step outside into my car. I am not chasing the aurora any more, I am chasing the section of the sky not covered with clouds. Randomly, I decide to explore north towards Dayton Highway. About an hour of driving at Alaskan scale, I'm pumped up on Red Bull. It's hard to see the sky and drive at the same time so I pull over many times. My determination to see the light show is now sprinkled with excitement when I start seeing highway signs for the North Pole and the Arctic Circle. I was within reach of the places I had only seen on TV but I couldn't get to them. Dayton Highway is not maintained so I cannot take my rental car beyond a certain point.  I turn around and start heading back, still waiting for a break in the clouds so I can catch a glimpse of the dancing lights above.&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I pull over into a turnout and see a truck ahead of me. It's equipped with guard rails, flood lights and bunch of extra tires. It belongs to Jeff, an Aurora-chaser, as I'd find out soon. And he is setting up his tripod to get ready to photograph. I feel hopeful despite my faltering faith in being able to see the aurora because his faith is strong. He helps me setup my phone to be able to capture pictures of the night sky as we wait. Before long, the clouds finally part their curtains. It's probably 4 am, but for me the show has just begun. I watch in awe at a mere green streak of light. It's fixed, not moving but unmistakable.&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While standing, shooting and watching the lights, Jeff informs me that I am putting myself at great risk by driving alone at this time in the night. "Is it the bears?", I ask innocently, as I always associated Alaska with Grizzly bears. "The moose, silly!", he laughs as he explained to me that it is the moose all Alaskans are scared of, not the bears. The 6 foot tall horse like counterpart of the deer is actually running freely through the parts of Alaskan highways that cut through forests and if a car runs into them, there will be serious damage to the car in the best case and probably even death of everyone involved in the worst case. Without network coverage, any encounter with wildlife could turn into staying out in the cold all night and more exposure to wildlife. At some point, I notice that he is mocking me, and all tourists who believe that Alaska was just another place to visit. The clouds cover us again and the show is over. He suggests I either follow his big moose-safe truck closely if I wish to continue exploring or just take my sorry-ass rental car get back to my cabin as soon as possible. I don't have enough gas to continue my chase, so I turn back to my cabin. I had driven out over an hour now and the drive back is long, but I am on high alert for any sign of moose and praying for safe drive back.&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It's 5 am now, I am back at the cabin. The clouds are gone and the sky is fully lit up with the northern lights. The show is in full swing and act 2 is even better. I make a hot cup of coffee and bundle up to take more pictures. I'm tired yet the coffee and the excitement from getting the front row seats to the Aurora Borealis keeps me going. The lights change direction, they snake up north sometimes and sometimes they form a large rainbow that disappears south. They are mostly bright green but you can see streaks of purple and white in the mix, and it's surreal. I stay up another 30 min or so despite the dropping temperature, taking pictures from all angles. My weariness has finally caught up with me now and I am ready to call it a night. A crazy and wonderful night.&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As I get warm and cozy in my cabin bed, I think to how silly I must have been to have ever doubted it. The owner of the AirBnB where I rented the cabin told me that the clouds have to clear at some point. Maybe I should have just waited it out, at the cabin instead of risking my life driving in the Alaskan terrain. But what if I hadn't and the clouds had never cleared? Waiting games are like bargaining to purchase a hand-carved wooden elephant from a street vendor in Mumbai, India. You never know if you caved in too soon or did just good. This game challenges your faith and makes you come face to face with the depths of your despair. Being attached to a specific outcome, makes you vulnerable. But when it's all said and done, the only question I ask myself is "Was it worth it? "&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="lifestyle"></category><category term="travelogue"></category></entry><entry><title>How I got there</title><link href="/2019/02/how-i-got-there-poem.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-02-18T10:20:00-08:00</published><updated>2021-08-01T17:06:24-07:00</updated><author><name>Sohani Rao</name></author><id>tag:None,2019-02-18:/2019/02/how-i-got-there-poem.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Here's an attempt to stay positive...&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;The path disappears again,&lt;br&gt;
Faces blurring into one another,&lt;br&gt;
Gasping for air, I look down,&lt;br&gt;
The depth of the fall is horrific,&lt;br&gt;
Maybe I am wrong to keep going,&lt;br&gt;
Maybe someone else spoke my words,&lt;br&gt;
I am all I need though,&lt;br&gt;
No man to save the day,&lt;br&gt;
But he just might, at the right time and place,&lt;br&gt;
Breathing life onto a journey still in the making,&lt;br&gt;
Just enough to keep me going for a bit longer,&lt;br&gt;
And then dropping me down this cliff,&lt;br&gt;
into a void so I can find myself all over again.&lt;br&gt;
Let it go, let it be, &lt;br&gt;
those words of wisdom,&lt;br&gt;
fail to comfort me, &lt;br&gt;
I know it's going to be okay,&lt;br&gt;
After darkness comes another day,&lt;br&gt;
and with it comes a possibility, just a possibility&lt;br&gt;
that I'll make it, out of this tunnel and into the light&lt;br&gt;
but this time, know exactly how I got there.&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="poem"></category><category term="poem"></category></entry><entry><title>Goodbyes on the camino</title><link href="/2018/12/goodbyes-on-the-camino-poem.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-12-26T10:20:00-08:00</published><updated>2021-08-08T18:40:02-07:00</updated><author><name>Sohani Rao</name></author><id>tag:None,2018-12-26:/2018/12/goodbyes-on-the-camino-poem.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Inspired by my hike to Camino de Santaigo along Camino de Frances in Christmas 2018.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I took a thousands steps, and I sat down,&lt;br&gt;
Think I'll just give this race up and take my bow,&lt;br&gt;
Maybe I am one of the lucky ones that got left out,&lt;br&gt;
Whatever season it was, it is over now&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
The sun will rise tomorrow and you will walk again,&lt;br&gt;
But I'll be packing my bags to go home instead,&lt;br&gt;
Yes you and I are not longer on the same page,&lt;br&gt;
But I am grateful for everything we did share&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Goodbye my darling, you are the love of my life,&lt;br&gt;
I'll think of who I was when you were by my side,&lt;br&gt;
I will weave every memory of us into a cozy blanket,&lt;br&gt;
And wear it to comfort me on these cold nights&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Before I go, there something you need to know,&lt;br&gt;
I gave it everything I had and then some more,&lt;br&gt;
That's why I can now walk away without remorse,&lt;br&gt;
Even when it hurts and cuts deep into my soul.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Don't worry about me, I will be okay,&lt;br&gt;
I am a fighter, a survivor as you say,&lt;br&gt;
Hug me a last time and wish me bon voyage,&lt;br&gt;
We should have said goodbye, when we had "a way"&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt; &lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="poem"></category><category term="poem"></category></entry><entry><title>Before the dawn breaks</title><link href="/2018/06/before-the-dawn-breaks-poem.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-06-18T10:20:00-07:00</published><updated>2021-08-01T17:05:57-07:00</updated><author><name>Sohani Rao</name></author><id>tag:None,2018-06-18:/2018/06/before-the-dawn-breaks-poem.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;There's power in community.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Ready for the last mile,&lt;br&gt;
Rising before the dawn breaks,&lt;br&gt;
Putting one foot in front of another,&lt;br&gt;
A light guiding our way,&lt;br&gt;
Feeling the pain of the past,&lt;br&gt;
And all that went wrong,&lt;br&gt;
Hand in hand in hand in hand,&lt;br&gt;
We march on strong,&lt;br&gt;
The gates will open wide,&lt;br&gt;
Our path will appear,&lt;br&gt;
The sun will shine so bright,&lt;br&gt;
The moon will disappear,&lt;br&gt;
As we reach the summit,&lt;br&gt;
The clouds bow down,&lt;br&gt;
Purple velvet turns crimson,&lt;br&gt;
And the future joins us,&lt;br&gt;
Out of air and out of breath,&lt;br&gt;
Take a moment to see,&lt;br&gt;
That we are the love we seek,&lt;br&gt;
And that we were always here.&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="poem"></category><category term="poem"></category></entry><entry><title>Breaking waves</title><link href="/2018/06/breaking-waves-poem.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-06-18T10:20:00-07:00</published><updated>2021-08-01T17:06:08-07:00</updated><author><name>Sohani Rao</name></author><id>tag:None,2018-06-18:/2018/06/breaking-waves-poem.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I once tried to learn how to surf, and...&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Sun shining on the blue seas,&lt;br&gt;
Inviting me in despite my fears,&lt;br&gt;
The warm air beats cold waters,&lt;br&gt;
A summer of hope is here.&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Waves crashing, churning, drowning,&lt;br&gt;
Sending me back, many strokes,&lt;br&gt;
Giving in, diving, tumbling, paddling,&lt;br&gt;
I try again, to get past the breaking waves.&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Maybe I am not strong enough,&lt;br&gt;
To get to where I can start to surf,&lt;br&gt;
To fail in all the right ways,&lt;br&gt;
And finally, get a chance to learn.&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Stop trying, it's time to give up,&lt;br&gt;
Let the ocean carry me to shores,&lt;br&gt;
Feel the warmth instead, lying in the sun,&lt;br&gt;
Mastering the art of letting go.&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="poem"></category><category term="poem"></category></entry><entry><title>Over The Bridge</title><link href="/2016/12/over-the-bridge.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-12-26T10:20:00-08:00</published><updated>2021-08-01T16:31:58-07:00</updated><author><name>Sohani Rao</name></author><id>tag:None,2016-12-26:/2016/12/over-the-bridge.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;My solo overnight hike at the Grand Canyon.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Before the crack of dawn in the thick of winter, the canyon was dark. I looked up to the sky lit up with stars framed by the walls of the canyon above me. I had spent the night at Phantom Ranch hostel in Grand Canyon and was about to hike up 5000 ft with my pack. With no more light that what I could see using the head lamps, I arrived at the silver bridge. The &lt;a href="https://grcahistory.org/sites/colorado-river-corridor/silver-bridge/"&gt;silver bridge&lt;/a&gt;  connects the Phantom Ranch hostel to the Bright Angel trail allowing the millions of hikers that attempt this trail to save 1.5 miles in total distance to the South Rim. But on this particular morning, I was alone. I had chosen a time of the year where it is easier to avoid crowds.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Arriving at the silver bridge around 5:30 am, I had regretted my decision to hike alone for the second time that morning. The first time was just 10 min ago when I had noticed a few pairs of moving eyes in the distance. I wasn't equipped to handle any wildlife should I encounter it. Relieved that those eyes belonged to mules, I had pushed on further into the trail. But now standing at one end of the silver bridge, my affirmation "I can do this!" had turned into a question "what am I doing?".&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
The silver bridge is 0.3 miles long. It takes 15 min to cross the bridge on foot. When you are on the bridge, it feels pretty scary even in broad daylight because you can hear the roaring waters beneath you. It is made of metal bars so you can see through it. However, crossing this bridge in the dark is far more unnerving. Our sense of hearing is heightened when the lights dim, to help us react to our environment better. And in this case, the sound of the river was almost defeaning. I could not see more than 1 feet ahead of me even with headlamps. The bridge railings were too far apart, so I couldn't hold on to them. With all I could see and hear, I just had to place one step after another on the metal belt right ahead of me.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
When I made it across the bridge, I looked back and drew a deep breath of awe. I instantly knew this was something I would not forget, regardless of all the other amazing wonders Grand Canyon had to offer me. The rest of the trail was challenging; some parts of the hike up to the South Rim were brutal. I had to take frequent breaks, put on crampons to hike the last 2 miles on snow and was exhausted by the time I reached the top. 
Today, more than 4 years later, it's that 15 min walk across the silver bridge I write about, not the hours I spent hiking down to the bottom and back up. Maybe 18 miles of hiking is a great accomplishment for some, but for me, it's fairly normal. No, I don't mean to brag but instead to say that it was a comfort zone for me. Every step taken on that bridge, however, was as much an act of faith as it was of surrender. Maybe that was the sense of adventure I came looking for. And at the time, bottom of the Grand Canyon seemed to be the only place it could be found. &lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="lifestyle"></category><category term="travelogue"></category></entry></feed>